Hello everybody and welcome to this tutorial.
أهلا ومرحبا بكم فى هذه الحلقة الجديدة من برنامجكم التعليمى.
Today I will show you how you can install aircrack and reaver.
اليوم سأريكم كيفية تثبيت aircrack and reaver
So aircrack is pretty simple.
حيث ان aircrack بسيط جدا
Just type in "yum install aircrack-ng"
فقط اكتب " yum install aircrack-ng"
and its gonna pick up the right version by default, so just go ahead and press ENTER
وسيقوم بإختيار الاصدار المناسب بشكل افتراضى لذلك فقط إمضى قدما
In Fedora, it runs through checks every time you call yum.
فى فيدورا، إنه يمر على فحوصات فى كل مرة تستدعى yum
You can pass -c argument and order that to do that it.
يمكنك تمرير حجة –c وأمره ان يفعل ذلك
It says package aircrack-ng is already installed and latest version.
انه يقول تم بالفعل تثبيت حزمة aircrack-ng وأحدث إصدار.
You might be prompted for a question along the way.
قد تتم مطالبتك بسؤال طوال الوقت.
If you want to skip that, just go ahead and type in " -y"
إذا كنت ترغب في تخطي ذلك، فقط إمضى قدما واكتب "-y"
That's it
هذا هو
With this command that I am selecting at the moment, installation will fly through.
مع هذا الامر الذى اختاره فى هذه اللحظة سيتم التنصيب بسرعة
You won't be prompted for any questions
لن يطلب منك أية أسئلة
and you will have aircrack-ng installed on your system without any problems.
وسيكون لديك aircrack-ng مثبت على النظام الخاص بك دون أي مشاكل.
However, Reaver is quite a different story.
ومع ذلك، Reaver هى قصة مختلفة تماما.
Reaver cannot be found in Fedora's repositories and therefore, it has to be downloaded from the net.
ريفر لا يمكن العثور عليها في مستودعات فيدورا، وبالتالي،
Now the there are lots of places to do this.
الآن هناك الكثير من الأماكن للقيام بذلك.
I have chosen to download it from Google Code.
وقد اخترت لتحميل البرنامج من مدونة جوجل.
That's basically the safest place from where you can download it
هذا في الأساس هو المكان الأكثر أمانا من حيث يمكنك تحميل البرنامج
and let's just go ahead open up my favorite browser, which is Firefox.
ودعونا فقط نمضي قدما ونفتح متصفحي المفضل، وهو الفايرفوكس.
You can open whatever you wish.
يمكنك فتح ما يحلو لك.
Type in "reaver google code"
اكتب " reaver google code"
It should pop up
يجب ان يظهر فجأة
Yep, this is it
نعم، هذا هو
There we go
ها نحن نذهب
Now we are on Google Code website, where we have Reaver VPS
الآن نحن على موقع مدونة جوجل، حيث لدينا Reaver VPS
You have a description here, and you have a pro version here.
لديك وصف هنا، وأيضا لديك نسخة للمحترفين هنا.
Basically the difference between the pro version and the one that we're getting for free
اساسا الفرق بين نسخة المحترفين والنسخة التى نحصل عليها مجانا
is this graphical user interface
هو واجهة المستخدم الرسومية تلك
which, I mean, let's face it
الذي، أعني، دعونا نواجه الأمر
if you're pen tester or a white hat hacker, you're not going to be using that much of guis
اذا كانت مختبر إختراقات او مخترق شريف، فلن تستخدم هذا القدر الكبير من التخفى
I mean, pretty much not at all.
أعني، الى حد كبير لا تخفى على الإطلاق.
This just means that it's gonna try pins in a certain order
هذا يعني فقط أنه سيجرب الاختراقات بترتيب معين
which is more likely to succeed than the default one, according to someone
والتي هي أكثر احتمالا للنجاح من الافتراضي، وفقا لشخص ما
but not necessarily true
ولكن ليس صحيحا بالضرورة
and integrated WEP cracking
والتكسير المدمج لل WEP
and as I said, you don't really need WEP
وكما قلت، أنت لا تحتاج حقا الى WEP
You're not gonna be able to find these days, pretty much anywhere.
لن تكون قادرا على ايجاده هذه الايام الى حد كبير فى اى مكان
If you do, as I said before, those people don't deserve to have wifi.
فإذا وجدته، كما قلت فى السابق، فهؤلاء الناس لا يستحقون امتلاك واى فاى
It's basically open wifi
انه اساسا واى فاى مفتوح
regardless of what sort of a password you put in.
بغض النظر عن نوع كلمة المرور التي وضعتها فيه.
Make sure you're not one of those people.
تأكد من أنك لست واحدا من هؤلاء الناس.
I mean, fine, okay
أعني، حسنا، نعم
somebody's going to be able to connect your network and all that
شخص ما سيكون قادرا على ربط شبكتك وكل هذا
but it opens up a route for a lot worse activity, something more malicious.
ولكنه يفتح الطريق لنشاط أسوأ بكثير، شيء أكثر خباثة.
Let's put it so they'll be able to reroute your traffic and do stuff of a kind
دعونا نضعها حتى يكونوا قادرين على توجيه إتصالك وعمل أشياء من هذا القبيل
and sniff it.
وشم ذلك.
Not a good idea.
ليست فكرة جيدة.
Just switch to WPA or WPA2
فقط تحول إلى WPA أو WPA2
Anyway, I'm gonna go ahead and click on Downloads, in the upper left corner
على أي حال، أنا سأمضي قدما وانقر على التحميل، في الزاوية اليسرى العليا
and there are different versions here that can be downloaded.
وهناك إصدارات مختلفة هنا يمكن تحميلها.
I mean, there are no fundamental differences in the way the reaver works in between these versions
أعنى انه لا توجد اختلافات جوهرية في الطريقة التى يعمل بهاreaver
but there are bugs fixes definitely in that, and that is very nice.
ولكن هناك إصلاحات للأخطاء بالتأكيد فى هذا وهذا لطيف جدا
It is maintained
انه يتم صيانته
There is support for it, and so on.
فهناك دعم له وما الى ذلك
So just go ahead and click on reaver 1.4.tar.gz
لذلك فقط امضى قدما واضغط على reaver 1.4.tar.gz
and it says  reaver 1.4.tar.gz here, file description, etc.
انه يقول هنا reaver 1.4.tar.gz وصف الملف، إلخ
This is the check sum
هذا هو الاختبار
You can use this in order to verify is your file intact, but I'm not gonna do that now.
يمكنك استخدام هذا للتأكد من ان ملفك سليم ولكننى لن أفعل هذا الان
I'm just go ahead and download it.
انا فقط سأمضى قدما وأنزله
Once it is downloaded, you can go ahead and open up the folder in which it actually exists
بمجرد تحميلها، يمكنك ان تمضي قدما وتفتح المجلد الذي هو موجود به بالفعل
and I have a lot of things here.
ولدى الكثير من الاشياء هنا
So it says I have different versions that I have downloaded from different sites
لذلك يقول لدي إصدارات مختلفة قمت بتحميلها من مواقع مختلفة
but if you find this package that I am selecting for you at the moment
ولكن إذا وجدت هذه الحزمة التى اختارها لك في الوقت الحالي
it says reaver 1.4 fc20
انه يقول reaver 1.4 fc20
The letters are pretty small.
الحروف صغيرة جدا
This is maximum that I can zoom it in.
وهذا هو الحد الأقصى الذي يمكنني تكبيره
Don't download it
لا تنزله
It doesn't work that well at all
أنه لا يعمل بشكل جيد على الإطلاق
It tends to break and the .rpm extension doesn't work quite as you would expect it to work.
انها تميل للإنكسار وإمتداد ال .rpm لا يعمل على نحو تام كما تتوقعه ان يعمل
Just download it from Google Code and compile it from source.
فقط حمل البرنامج من مدونة جوجل وجمعه من المصدر
There's no reason why not do it, especially when you have me showing you in detail how to do it.
ليس هناك سبب لعدم فعل ذلك، وخاصة عندما أكون كوجود هنا لأريك بالتفصيل
So just go ahead and double click on this file.
إذ فقط إمضي قدما وانقر نقرا مزدوجا على هذا الملف.
You can extract it through a GUI method.
يمكنك استخراجه من خلال أسلوب واجهة المستخدم الرسومية.
It's far simpler.
انها أبسط كثيرا
You can also extract it through the terminal
يمكنك أيضا استخراجه من خلال محطة
but I'm just gonna go ahead and use GUI for this occasion.
ولكن أنا فقط سأمضي قدما واستخدام واجهة المستخدم الرسومية فى هذه المناسبة.
This is one of the advantages of Linux over Windows.
هذه هي واحدة من نقاط تفوق لينكس على الويندوز.
By default, it will be able to unpack pretty much anything.
افتراضيا، ستكون قادرة على فكه الى حد كبير أي شيء.
Zip, tar, WinRar, whatever it's going to be able to unpack it, no problem
كل ما أريدها أن تكون قادرة على فكه، لا مشكلة
which is fantastic.
وهي رائعة.
No extra insulation needed; this is all installed by default.
لا يوجد اى تنصيب اضافى مطلوب. فكل شيء مثبت بشكل افتراضي.
So let's just go ahead and click on extract.
لذلك دعونا فقط نمضي قدما وننقر على استخراج
Now where do I want to extract?
الآن أين أريد أن استخراج؟
Let's say to desktop because I'm gonna delete it anyway
دعونا نقول لسطح المكتب لأنني سأحذفه على أي حال
as I already do have it installed.
إذ انا بالفعل أملكها منصبة
So just go ahead and press Okay
إذ فقط إمضي قدما واضغط حسنا Okay
and yeah, I've just told it to do it twice. Oh well.
ونعم، لقد قلت لها فقط أن تفعل ذلك مرتين. اوه حسناً.
Apply to all, override
طبقها على كل شيء، تجاوز
We're not going to lose a lot of time there, as the extraction process is relatively fast.
نحن لن نفقد الكثير من الوقت هناك، حيث أن عملية الاستخراج سريعة نسبيا.
Okay, so let's just go ahead and go back to our terminal
حسنا، لذلك دعونا فقط نمضي قدما ونعود الى محطتنا
navigate over to desktop
انتقل الى سطح المكتب
"cd /home/Chronic/Desktop/
"cd /home/Chronic/Desktop/
and do I have it here?
هل هى لدى هنا؟
Yep, there we go.
نعم، وها نحن نذهب
"clear"
"clear"
Let me just show you that I do in fact have it.
دعنى فقط أريك اننى فى الحقيقة أملكه
It's much neater if I do it like this
انها أكثر إتقانا بكثير إذا فعلتها كذلك
and there we go.
وها نحن نذهب
reaver-1.4/
reaver-1.4/
Let's navigate over to that folder.
دعونا تنقل الى هذا المجلد.
Clear the screen, list the contents of the directory, go to docs
مسح الشاشة، سرد محتويات الدليل، انتقل إلى المستندات
Let's just go ahead and  see what is there
دعونا فقط نمضي قدما ونرى ماذا هناك
and you might think that I'm some sort of an expert or something of a kind
وربما تعتقد أنني خبير أو شئ كذلك
that I just do these things out of my head.
فقط لأننى أفعل هذه الأشياء من رأسي.
No. People create readme files for a reason.
لا أحد ينشئ ملفات readme لسبب
They are there to be read, because the developer has left specific instructions on how to do something.
إنهم هناك ليتم قرائتهم، لأن المطور قد ترك تعليمات محددة بشأن كيفية
So let's just go ahead and cat it.
لذلك دعونا فقط نمضي قدما ونلتقطه.
Excellent
ممتاز
So the following are Reaver source files.
إذ فالتالى هم ملفات المصدر ريفر Reaver
So it has the description of what is located in each one of these files
لذلك فهى لديها وصف لما يوجد فى كل واحد من هذه الملفات
So you have 80211.c
إذ انت لديك 80211.c
Functions for reading, sending, and parsing 802.11 management frames
وظائف للقراءة، والإرسال، وتحليل 802.11 أطر الإدارة
802.11 is a standard, as I said before
802.11 هو المعيار، كما قلت من قبل
but look at this --
ولكن أنظر لهذا -
The developer has actually left the entire installation process here.
المطور قد ترك فعلا عملية التثبيت بأكملها هنا.
You have every single command that you need to run explained in detail
لديك كل أمر منفرد تريد ان تنفذه مشروح بالتفصيل
what it does, and how you can open and execute it.
وماذا يعمل وكيف تفتحه وتنفذه
This is wonderful
هذا رائع
and that is why I say when you download something, when you unzip it
وهذا هو السبب في أننى أقول انك عندما تحميل شيء، وعندما تفك ضغط شئ
just go ahead and find the readme file.
فقط امضى قدما واعثر على ملف إقرأنى readme
It's there for a reason.
انه هناك لسبب ما.
People do tend to leave instructions there on how to do something
الناس يميلون إلى ترك تعليمات هناك على كيفية القيام بشيء ما
and they most likely encounter the same problems that you might have encountered.
والأرجح أنهم يواجهون نفس المشاكل التي كنت قد واجهتها.
So you can even see possible solutions.
حتى تستطيع أن ترى الحلول الممكنة.
Anyway, you can check this inscription out.
على أي حال، يمكنك فحص هذه الكتابة.
Uh...Not inscription, but the text.
اه ... ليس الكتابة، ولكن النص.
Reaver is only supported on the Linux platform, requires the libpcap and libsqlite librarie
Reaver مدعوم فقط على منصة لينكس ويتطلب libpcap and libsqlite librarie
and can be built and installed by running the following commands
ويمكن بناؤه وتثبيته عن طريق تشغيل الاوامر التالية
and so execute the configuration script, make, make install
لتنفيذ برنامج التهيئة، وعمل، عمل التهيئة
That's it
هذا هو
It even tells you how to actually install it.
انه حتى يخبرك كيفية تثبيته فعليا.
So they're there for a reason.
لذلك فهم هناك لسبب ما.
Anyway, of course you cannot run the configuration file from here.
على أي حال، وبطبيعة الحال لا يمكنك تشغيل ملف التهيئة من هنا.
You need to reverse course and go to source
تحتاج إلى تغيير اتجاهه والذهاب الى المصدر
Let's see what's in there...
دعونا نرى ما هو موجود هناك...
There we go
وها نحن نذهب
We have configure
لدينا تهيئة
and you can see by default here, it's executable.
ويمكنك أن ترى افتراضيا هنا، انه قابل للتنفيذ.
If I just give you a longer listing
إذا أنا فقط أعطيتك قائمة أطول
It has an x permission here, here, and here.
انها لديها إذن x هنا وهنا وهنا
So the user has it, and the group has it as well.
إذ فالمستخدم يملكه، والمجموعة تملكه كذلك
Anyway, type in "./configure"
على اية حال، اكتب ""./configure
So now it's checking for stuff.
إذ انها تتحقق من الاشياء الان.
It has it's dependencies, without which it cannot function.
انها لديها التبعيات الخاصة بها والتى بدونها لا يمكن ان تعمل
Type in "make"
اكتب " make"
There we go
وها نحن نذهب
It's running through
انها تعمل
So I didn't do anything out of my head here.
إذ إنني لم أفعل أي شيء من رأسي هنا.
I just went on the web, I found the safest place I can find to download the code from
أنا فقط ذهبت إلى شبكة الإنترنت، ووجدت أكثر مكان آمن لتحميل الكود منه
and I'm compiling it here, as the developer of the code instructed me to do it
وأنا أجمعه هنا، كما أمرنى مطور الكود ان افعله
and the instructions aren't that complicated.
والإرشادات ليست بهذا التعقيد.
It's just three commands
انها ثلاثة أوامر فقط
and the final command is "make install"
والأمر الأخير هو "عمل التثبيت" " make install"
Now it's gonna give me a lot of errors here...
الآن انها ستعطيني الكثير من الأخطاء هنا ...
Well, not errors, but warnings
حسنا، لا أخطاء، ولكن التحذيرات
primarily because I already have it installed.
في المقام الأول لأنني بالفعل قد حصلت عليها منصبة.
I need to clear this out and then be able to install this
انا احتاج الى مسح هذا وبعدها أن أكون قادرا على تنصيب ذلك
but that's not gonna happen, primarily because I do have reaver installed.
ولكن هذا لن يحدث، أساسا لأننى لدى reaver منصب
So let's just go ahead and check one more time if there is anything else that we've left out.
لذلك دعونا فقط نمضى قدما ونفحص مرة أخرى ما اذا كان هناك شيئا اخر تركناه
If I can reach it
اذا كنت استطيع الوصول اليها
Yep, there we go.
نعم، وها نحن نذهب.
So no, I haven't left anything out.
لذلك لا، أنا لم أترك أي شيء.
Basically, the last command for you will run.
أساسا الامر الاخير بالنسبة لك سيعمل
For me, it won't
بالنسبة لي، فإنه لن يعمل
primarily because I already have reaver installed on my system.
في المقام الأول لأنني بالفعل لدىreaver مثبت على نظام التشغيل الخاص بى.
If there are any problems, feel free to post it in the question section.
إذا كان هناك أي مشاكل، لا تتردد في ارسالهم على ذلك في قسم الاسئلة.
I will be more than happy to help you out.
سأكون أكثر من سعيد لمساعدتك.
Let's go ahead and clear this out.
دعونا نمضي قدما ونمسح ذلك.
So type in "reaver --help"
إذ أكتب " reaver -–help"
Excellent
ممتاز
It is installed, it is functional, it is responsive to our commands
لقد تم تثبيته، انه يعمل، انه يستجيب لأوامرنا
and here's the syntax for reaver.
وها هو بناء الجملة الخاص ب reaver
This is the basic syntax.
هذه هي الجملة الأساسية.
Of course you can pass all of these arguments through it
بالطبع يمكنك تمرير كل هذه الحجج من خلال ذلك
and there are quite a lot of them.
وهناك الكثير جدا منها.
Basically what you say is "-i" for network interfaceand "-b" for BSSID
اساسا ما تقوله انت لواجهة الشبكة هو "-i" و "-b"
Over the MAC address, put quite simply.
على عنوان ماك، ضعهم بمنتهى البساطة
For the MAC address here, you have it.
لعنوان ماك هنا، انت تملكه
This is just a sample MAC address that has been generically placed here
هذا مجرد عينة لعنوان ماك تم وضعها هنا بشكل عام
and of course, we have even for reaver
وبالطبع، لدينا حتى لريفر reaver
-vv for double verbose output, which is fantastic.
vvلنتيجة مطولة مزدوجة وهي رائعة.
Let's just go ahead and clear the screen.
دعونا فقط نمضي قدما ونمسح الشاشة.
That was a way in which you could have installed aircrack and reaver in Linux
كانت هذه طريقة تستطيع من خلالها تثبيت aircrack and reaver
but just in case you are a Windows user, I'll show you how to do it in Windows.
ولكن فقط في حال كنت من مستخدمي ويندوز، سأريك كيف تفعل ذلك في ويندوز.
Until then, I bid you farewell.
حتى ذلك الحين، أودعكم.